<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ray ZZ</title>
    <description>Your destination for solving hyper-dimensional Rubik's Cubes, experimenting with microtonality, and stalking my course plans. Also, I don't even know ZZ.
</description>
    <link>http://www.rayzz.me//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.rayzz.me//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 01:54:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 01:54:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Analysis of FSI learning times for French and Japanese</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last three weeks I have been working mainly on three things: side projects, professional development coursework, and preparation for Newmarket Open 2017, a Rubik’s cube competition. Anyway, the last item is out of the way and the second-last item is nearly out of the way, so let’s continue with the posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall that last time I said that I would take the Foreign Service Institute’s language learning times list and compare it to the Core French curriculum. For fun, I’ll also examine how long Japanese could take to learn for my friends, but first let’s find out what the Foreign Service Institute (FSI) has for us…&lt;!-- MORE --&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Wikibooks:Language_Learning_Difficulty_for_English_Speakers&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for people who only speak English, we can learn French up to some “general professional proficiency” in 600 hours. This means that one hour of learning a day extends to knowing French very well in under two years, but would this mean that four hours of studying French a day allows us to gain a “professional level” of proficiency in under half a year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really. According to the Wikibooks article, we already know some reasons why these learners can learn so quickly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Those working in the FSI already have a knack for picking up languages quickly as they serve as professional translators.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The listed hours are only for class hours, meaning each learner must study the language for three to four additional hours per day on their own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The self-study hours are directed, so it’s probably not as simple as just picking their favourite song in their target language and listening to it on repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with this in mind, let’s first increase the given times by 25% so that we require 750 class hours. Meanwhile, I took Core French from grades 4 to 11 but failed to have a conversation in only French with anyone in Montreal, so something must have went wrong…let’s see how many class hours I got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A school year in Ontario requires &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/general/list/calendar/holidaye.html&quot;&gt;at least 194 days&lt;/a&gt;. Then, there are 8 years from grades 4 to 11 so I had 1552 class hours of French right? Well, I forgot how often I had French in School, but it definitely wasn’t every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let’s cancel out grades 4 to 6 since during those grades I learned nothing. From grades 7 to 9, I had 50 minutes a day and 2.5 days/5 days a week. From grades 10 to 12, I had 75 minutes a day and also 2.5 days/5 days a week since French only took up one semester per year. By my calculations, this results in 29100 minutes in total, which sounds impressive until you realize it’s 485 hours. We’re still missing at least 265 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make this slightly more interesting, let’s consider taking grade 12 French. Then, the estimate goes up to 606 hours. Also, in university, there’s only 3 hours of class a week per subject and 12 weeks per term, so every term if I keep taking French I would have 36 more class hours per course, meaning to reach 750 hours from 606 hours would require me to take exactly 4 more French courses in university, which is actually what I expected for the amount of time required to reach a truly competent level of speaking and reading in French with a Core French high school background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, the FSI does not seem too far-fetched here. Furthermore, taking more French courses in university might not be the worst idea, but I already have other electives planned and I already lost most if not all of my motivation after failing so often in Montreal, so I’ll blame the Core French curriculum for making me even feel competent before working there and move on to learning other languages, such as Japanese…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…This isn’t the smartest idea. Wikibooks lists it as requiring 2200 class hours, along with a warning that it would be slightly more difficult than other languages such as Mandarin or Arabic. Note that since we are talking about native English speakers, it makes some sense. But, I already know some Mandarin, so I shouldn’t need that many hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my friends who are taking Japanese courses watch &lt;del&gt;too much&lt;/del&gt; anime, so they also shouldn’t need that many hours…in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, let’s see what Waterloo provides – JAPAN 101 is a 12-week course with 3 hours per week of lecture and tutorial combined. Then, we have 36 class hours. To get 2200 class hours we will need 61 courses. That’s more courses than I’ll take in my entire undergraduate career, so good luck to my friends I guess. But, let’s say somehow anime actually works as class hours and that my friends consistently watch 5 hours of anime a day on weekdays and 9 hours a day on weekends. This hypothesis is almost as ridiculous as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spherical_cow&quot;&gt;spherical cows&lt;/a&gt;, but it’ll do to prevent both blog-reader and blog-writer from falling asleep, even though there’s only half a paragraph left. Then, we have that my friends would watch 2236 hours of anime a year, so they’re done after just 1 year! Clearly, they haven’t achieved this in reality yet…it must be the fact that they’re watching with English subtitles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next time when we check out the expected rate of toilet paper usage within a dorm of 4, and compare it to the amount of toilet paper I had to supply last term!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.rayzz.me//2017/06/18/fsi-analysis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.rayzz.me//2017/06/18/fsi-analysis.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lotto 6/49 Odds Represented By Dice Rolls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lotto 6/49 is a Canadian lottery game where you get to choose 6 of 49 numbers for 3 dollars, and have a chance at winning millions. Now, the chance of choosing all six numbers correctly is 1 in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;49 \choose 6&lt;/script&gt;, or 1 in approximately 13 million, which already sounds low. Hence, it’s easy to forget how small of a chance you really have at this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, here’s a Haskell program fragment that puts things into perspective by first calculating the number of coin tosses that you would need to guess correctly in a row such that the chance of doing so is as low or even lower than winning the lottery…
&lt;!-- MORE --&gt;
Then, it gives the same for six-sided dice rolls, and twenty-sided dice rolls respectively. As a bonus, it also considers the equivalents to choosing 4 out of 6 numbers correctly, which still gives you a few thousand dollars as a reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note I left out the main method since it just prints out a bunch of stats that you’ll see later anyway. Also, the recursive choose method is comfy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-haskell&quot; data-lang=&quot;haskell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Main&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid param&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;otherwise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ceil_log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ceil_log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid param&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;otherwise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ceiling&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logBase&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fromIntegral&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fromIntegral&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the output?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
You need to correctly guess 24 coin tosses  
OR 10 6-sided dice rolls  
OR 6 20-sided dice rolls to win the 6/49 lottery.  
  
You need to correctly guess 18 coin tosses  
OR 7 6-sided dice rolls  
OR 5 20-sided dice rolls to win the 4/49 lottery.  

Good Luck!

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok sure, but what if one or more of these numbers are overestimated by several degrees of magnitude, especially since we always round up the number of coin flips or dice rolls to make them integers? Well, there’s only one way to find out. Let’s add a function that calculates how off an estimate is, and get the main method to print some new numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-haskell&quot; data-lang=&quot;haskell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;get_magnitudes_off&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Float&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;get_magnitudes_off&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;estimate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;actual_num&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;estimate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;actual_num&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid params&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;otherwise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logBase&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fromIntegral&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;actual_num&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fromIntegral&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;estimate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the new output is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
Lotto 6/49 estimation results for 6 numbers:
Coin flips: 12.643154 magnitudes off.
Six-sided die rolls: 1.5726068 magnitudes off.
20-sided die rolls: 1.5138803 magnitudes off.

Lotto 6/49 estimation results for 4 numbers:
Coin flips: 10.815703 magnitudes off.
Six-sided die rolls: 8.266034 magnitudes off.
20-sided die rolls: 0.8481274 magnitudes off.

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT use coin flips to estimate your chances at winning four or six numbers of Lotto 6-49 for you’ll be at least ten orders of magnitude off. This means your estimated probability at winning the lottery is at least 10 billion times smaller than the actual probability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do use 20-sided dice to estimate your chances at winning four or six numbers of Lotto 6-49 for you’ll be at most just two orders of magnitude off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, remember that if you can often guess five or six rolls of a 20-sided die correctly in a row, you can win the Lotto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who are only familiar with cubic six-sided dice,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;If you can often guess 10 rolls of the 6-sided die correctly in a row (I doubt it), you can win the jackpot&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun playing now that you know this, and see you next time when we find out how long it should take to learn French according to the Foreign Service Institute, and how the Ontario Core French curriculum does in comparison!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.rayzz.me//2017/05/31/lottery-dice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.rayzz.me//2017/05/31/lottery-dice.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Largest Comfortable Cube Size and the Decision To Buy A Gigaminx</title>
        <description>&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS_CHTML&quot;&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am considering buying a gigaminx partly out of boredom and partly
for the purpose of having something to turn for half an hour straight
when there’s nothing else to do, such as when waiting for MiWay buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference, here is how the gigaminx looks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0169/0924/products/Shengshou_Gigaminx_White02_1024x1024.jpg?v=1452828270&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a white gigaminx from cubedepotusa&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, being the picky cuber I am, I state that &lt;strong&gt;I will only buy the gigaminx if it contains fewer cubies than the 9x9x9 Rubik’s Cube&lt;/strong&gt;. This is because I’m OK with solving a 9x9x9, but anything above really gets tiring. Thus, let’s first calculate the number of cubies in a 9x9x9:
&lt;!-- MORE --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 8 vertices so we have at least 8 cubies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 12 edges each with 7 cubies so that gives us 84 more cubies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 6 centers each with 7*7 = 49 cubies so we add on 294 more cubies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we have a total of 386 cubies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s calculate the number of cubies in a gigaminx:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 20 vertices so we have at least 20 cubies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 30 edges each with 3 cubies so that gives us 90 more cubies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 12 centers each with 11 cubies so that gives us 132 more cubies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we have a total of &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; 242 cubies. Now I actually want a gigaminx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But&lt;/strong&gt;, what really interests me more than the gigaminx itself would have to be the following question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;focus&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For some integer &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m \ge 2&lt;/script&gt;, what is the smallest &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt; Rubik’s cube such that the number of cubies it contains is greater than the number of cubies the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; megaminx contains?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counting the number of cubies the Rubik’s cube contains is not hard – if you think about it as a subtraction problem rather than an addition problem, it’s just &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n^3 - (n-2)^3&lt;/script&gt; for an &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt; Rubik’s cube. But, we can simplify it by factoring it as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(n-(n-2))(n^2 + n(n-2) + (n-2)^2) = 6n^2 - 12n + 8&lt;/script&gt;, not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the real question is the number of cubies the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt;x&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; megaminx contains. We know that there are at least 20 cubies since there are 20 vertices, and we know that there are &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;30(m-2)&lt;/script&gt; edge pieces, so we have a total of at least &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;20 + 30(m-2)&lt;/script&gt; cubies, but it’s the centers that are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider two cases: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; is odd, or &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; is even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; is odd, we have the megaminx, gigaminx, teraminx, etc. In these cases, the puzzle contains fixed centers, and T-centers exist. The number of cubies
&lt;em&gt;per center&lt;/em&gt; is then &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1 + 5(m-3)/2 + 5((m-3)/2)^2&lt;/script&gt;, so we have a total of
&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;20 + 30(m-2) + [12 + 30(m-3) + 15(m-3)^2] = 15m^2 - 30m + 17&lt;/script&gt; cubies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; is even, we have the kilominx, master kilominx, and I’m not sure what the 6x6x6 minx is called &lt;em&gt;(edit: it’s called the elite kilominx)&lt;/em&gt;. Anyway, the number of cubies &lt;em&gt;per center&lt;/em&gt; for those is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;5((m-2)/2)^2&lt;/script&gt;, so we have a total of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;20 + 30(m-2) + 15(m-2)^2 = 15m^2 - 30m + 20&lt;/script&gt; cubies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem to suggest that the master kilominx has more cubies than the gigaminx, but remember that for the master kilominx, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m = 4&lt;/script&gt;, so we have 140 cubies, whereas for the gigaminx we must plug in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m = 5&lt;/script&gt; to obtain 242 cubies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the inequality, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;6n^2-12n+8 &gt; 15m^2-30m+17&lt;/script&gt; for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; odd or &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;6n^2-12n+8 &gt; 15m^2-30m+20&lt;/script&gt; for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; even, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n &gt; m, m \ge 2&lt;/script&gt;. We want to find the smallest &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt; for some given &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; that satisfies these conditions. Since I am too lazy to solve this by hand, I wrote a small Clojure program that solves this for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m&lt;/script&gt; from 2 to 15 for me. Note that the 15x15x15 minx is the yottaminx, and yotta is the largest prefix on the SI scale, so I’m not going to consider any larger sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-program&quot;&gt;The program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I’m transferring over to Clojure from Racket and so I don’t know how to use all its idioms yet. Sorry for any eyesores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-clojure&quot; data-lang=&quot;clojure&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;ns &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;cube-mega-bounds.core&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-mega-size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-cube-size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;max-mega-size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;;; We have to assume that n is never already way over&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;defn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;-find-first-n-over&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;upper-bound&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;= &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;upper-bound&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;-find-first-n-over&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;inc &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;upper-bound&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;defn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;solve-ineq&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;num-mega-cubies&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;-find-first-n-over&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;num-mega-cubies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;defn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;solve-cube-ineq&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;+ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-12&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;zero? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;mod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; 
                   &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;+ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-30&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                   &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;+ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;* &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-30&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m-values&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-mega-size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;inc &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;max-mega-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;map &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;solve-ineq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-cube-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;m-values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;defn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;pretty-print&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;counters&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;min-mega-size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;inc &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;max-mega-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;doseq &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;map list &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;counters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Megaminx of size %dx%dx%d has fewer cubies &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;than a cube of size %dx%dx%d.\n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;defn &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;-main&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;solve-cube-ineq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;pretty-print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 2x2x2 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 3x3x3.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 3x3x3 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 5x5x5.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 4x4x4 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 6x6x6.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 5x5x5 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 8x8x8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 6x6x6 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 9x9x9.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 7x7x7 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 11x11x11.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 8x8x8 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 13x13x13.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 9x9x9 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 14x14x14.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 10x10x10 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 16x16x16.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 11x11x11 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 17x17x17.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 12x12x12 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 19x19x19.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 13x13x13 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 20x20x20.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 14x14x14 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 22x22x22.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Megaminx of size 15x15x15 has fewer cubies than a cube of size 24x24x24.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, not only does the gigaminx have fewer pieces than the 9x9x9 Rubik’s cube, but the 6x6x6 minx &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; has fewer pieces than the 9x9x9 Rubik’s cube. Doesn’t mean I’ll buy the latter, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next time when we find out how many coin flips or rolls of a single 6-sided die you’ll have to guess correctly to win the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.rayzz.me//2017/05/26/largest-comfortable-cube-size.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.rayzz.me//2017/05/26/largest-comfortable-cube-size.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
